Syed Murtaza Qamar

Gujrat District, Punjab, Pakistan



murtaza.qamar1001@gmail.com



+923480441558



linkedin.com/in/syed-murtaza-gamar-a825a9a1

Summary

Building quality websites and applications with cutting edge technologies while maintaining the Web Standards . Working in all kinds of web apps like From E commerce , Management System to the Real Time Apps

Well-rounded experience in MERN development, and object-oriented techniques.

Key skills include:

Proficient in Nodejs , ExpressJs, KoaJs , Javascript ES5/ES6, HTML, MVC Architecture , REST Architecture , and JSON.

Blockchain: WEB3.0, Solidity, Smart Contracts, IOTA

Experience with RethinkDB, MongoDB, Ajax, Source control tools [GITHUB Commands]

Good in ReactJS, TypeScript, Build Tools [webpack].

DevOps: Github, Netlify, Herokuapp, Amazon EC2, S3 Buckets, Cloudinary

Project Management: Trello, Slack

TOOLS Atom, Webstorm, MongoLab, RoboMongo, VisualStudioCode

Experience



Senior Software Engineer

GulzarSoft

May 2019 - Present (3 years 4 months +)

Working as a Senior Software developer and also as a Team lead for our company clients Main responsibilities include Developing Software using MERN STACK and Blockchain Technologies other skills Includes Communication with Company clients

requirement gatherings

Making project Plan

Feasibility and scope of the project

Developing Software Apllications

Allocating Resources

Design Architecture of System

Guiding Teams

Meb Developer

Nexthon

Jul 2017 - Dec 2018 (1 year 6 months)

working as a web developer in the PHP coreigniter Framework, MySql , AJax , REACTJS

Software Engineer

Moftak Solutions

Sep 2016 - May 2017 (9 months)

Web Application development, Server, Databases,

NodeJS, RethinkDb, NoSql, GitHub, Koa Js

Web Application Developer

ZAWN Technologies

Dec 2015 - Apr 2016 (5 months)

Responsibilites include building backend services mostly backend technlogies like NOdejs and databases

Android Developer

Jolta Technologies

Nov 2014 - Feb 2015 (4 months)

its intern ship . from very Beginners level to full stack Developer

Junior Android Developer

Jolta Technologies

Oct 2014 - Feb 2015 (5 months)

develop andorid base application

Education

University of Gujrat

Bachelor of Science (BS), Computer Science

2011 - 2015

University of Gujrat

Bachelor of Science (BS), Computer Science

2011 - 2015

In University, I was in team which was made for the Process of New Admissions in University.

I done Data Entry including authenticating Information In process of Admissions

University of Gujrat

BS Computer Science, Software Development

2011 - 2015

Skills

PHP • ES6 • React.js • Blockchain • Smart Contracts • IOTA • Ethereum • Amazon EC2 • Amazon S3 • DigitalOcean